
 <req_document>
 
     <p id="4.">
         <title>REQUIREMENTS</title>
         <p id="4.1">
             <title>REQUIRED STATES AND MODES</title>
             <text_body>
                 <itemize>
                     <item>Environmental Mode: This is the real-time operations that must react to varying 
 degrees of readiness to full scale wartime operations such as crisis planning with
  the use of heterogeneous data types and sources, transfer capabilities, data management
  services.</item>
                     <item>XML Services shall be segmented. COE sponsors shall adhere 
 to compliance level requirements described in the I&amp;RTS. </item>
                     <item>In the fixed (static) mode of operation (base or data processing megacenter), the
  data management services shall have the capability of being tuned by on-site personnel
  to adjust for varying workloads and sizes of associated databases. These workloads and
  databases are expected to change more frequently and to a greater extent than for 
 processing associated with deployed units</item>
                     <item>In a changing (dynamic) environment, such as with deployed units, the workload
  and database sizes may be more predetermined (given a more precise mission) and 
 require access to fewer data management administrative capabilities than needed in a 
 fixed environment. The XS shall have the ability to redefine or reset names of connect 
 descriptors to database server instances. Connect descriptors are fully qualified object 
 names and include address (protocol/host/port) and instance name. </item>
                     <item>In a degraded communications environment, there is a need, for example, to 
 be able to reset session time-out values if the data management services are being
  accessed by users affected by the communications degradation. At a minimum, the 
 session time-out values shall be user definable and be able to be reset prior to 
 initialization of a user session. The goal is to provide the option of dynamically changing
 session time values based on current communications performance identified by 
 capabilities of the network management or DBMS. </item>
                     <item>End User Mode: Portion of XS services shall be used by various classes of
  users: data consumers, data and database managers, network information infrastructure
  resource managers. Some of these uses of the data management services will entail 
 unique requirements that shall be fulfilled within the capability of XS services.</item>
                     <item>Maintenance Mode: This mode includes modification and/or addition of 
 application data segments, user permission, privileges, and restructuring storage
 and memory areas. In addition, maintenance also shall pertain to shutdown, open 
 not-mounted and online/off-line implementations, modifications, upgrade, or other 
 related actions. The data management services shall support managing various types
  of data, database architectures and platforms that includes hardware and software at
  the specified sites. </item>
                     <item>In support of training activities, the data management services 
 shall provide for the same processing as would be encountered in a production
  environment. However, access to the database may be via a training application 
 access to the DBMS rather than from the production mission application.</item>
                 </itemize>
             </text_body>
         </p>
         <p id="4.2">
             <title>XML SERVICES CAPABILITY REQUIREMENTS</title>
 
             <p id="Figure 3.2-1">
                 <p id="1">
                     <title>Register Terms and Structures (e.g., tags, DTDs, DCDs)</title>
                     <text_body>
                         <itemize>
                             <item>
 Producer services A producer is an agent that contributes metadata for inclusion into an
  XML Registry for the purposes of ensuring maximum semantic understanding of a term 
 as it appears in an XML document. To contribute metadata to a registry, the producer 
 must be able to receive XML registry forms, submit metadata and the related information
  resource artifacts, and notify.
                                 <itemize>
                                     <item>Produce and display submittal forms as part of the Information Resource
  Submittal Package from the web containing the following Information Resource
  artifacts: XML Tag Specification, XML Spec (i.e. DTD, DCD etc.), Sample of XML document
  of the tag to be submitted. The Package is to be compressed and emailed or sent ftp to 
 an addressee.</item>
                                     <item>Download Information Resource Submittal Package from the web containing 
 forms, instructions, and tools for submission to XML Registry.</item>
                                     <item>Submit prescribed metadata related to information resource type, information 
 resource association, status code, data types specified and other related information 
 specified in Appendix A within a combination of forms. These forms are part of the 
 Information Resource Submittal Package containing the following Information Resource
  artifacts: XML Tag Specification, XML Spec (i.e. DTD, DCD etc.), Sample of XML
  document of the tag to be submitted. The Package is to be compressed and emailed 
 or sent ftp to an addressee.</item>
                                 </itemize>
                             </item>
                             <item>
 A consumer examines a registry to select a tag structure for reuse in one
  or more applications that will exchange data according to a pre-defined agreement.
                                 <itemize>
                                     
                                     <item>View the XML Tags with the following relationships:
                                         <itemize>
                                             <item>Ancestor/ Descendant relationship: Provide the capability
  to view a Tag’s origin </item>
                                             <item>Uses/Used by relationship: Provide the capability to view a complex 
 Container Tag’s parent/child relationship</item>
                                             <item>Data type information: Provide the capability to view a tag’s data type
  and related information.</item>
                                             <item>Versioning relationship: Provide the capability to view an Information 
 resource’s versions</item>
                                             <item>Reference Sets: Provide the capability to view text related to the domai
  values or the related reference set</item>
                                             <item>Amplifying information: Provide the capability to view other information 
 resources such as ERwin models, DTDs, documents, etc., which describe or 
 otherwise provide amplifying information.</item>
                                             <item>View the XML Tags via a tree/hierarchy structure or tabular format.</item>
                                             <item>View the XML Tags by giving the user multiple search 
 options to find a specific Tag.</item>
                                             <item>View the XML tags by giving the user the search option to find all 
 tags of a given subscriber/author.</item>
                                         </itemize>
                                     </item>
                                     <item>Each Information Resource will have its own web page to allow the user 
 to view all pertinent information, according to its information resource type.</item>
                                     <item>View the Information Resource Submittal Package containing the following 
 Information Resource artifacts: XML Tag Specification, XML Spec 
 (i.e. DTD, DCD etc.), Sample of XML document of the tag to be submitted.</item>
                                     <item>Display an XML Tag Specification form to the author of a given information 
 resource. This XML Tag Spec will be used for inputting the requesting information
  for a specific Information Resource. </item>
                                     <item>Provide capabilities to download the XML Tags or other
 selected Information Resources.</item>
                                     <item>Catalog entities and attributes within servers to enable browsing, 
 searching, retrieving of data related to XML sources. </item>
                                     <item>Process ANSI standard SQL as specified in FIPS PUB 127-2</item>
                                     <item>Establish rules to ensure maximum semantic understanding 
 of a term as it appears in an XML document</item>
                                     <item>Provide a capability to subscribe for notification of changes to 
 Communities of Interest (COE) or Information Resources.</item>
                                 </itemize>
                             </item>
 
                             <item>
 Manager services
                                 <itemize>
                                     <item>Establish acceptable naming convention not to be in conflict with the DOD data 
 standards convention and establish a relationship to other naming conventions.</item>
                                     <item>Create a naming structure within the COE architecture to express the context 
 and relationship of the naming convention to other naming conventions 
 specified in the I&amp;RTS.</item>
                                     <item>Define a set of metadata tags, information attributed to metadata tags 
 (meta-metadata) and other related terms for the maintenance 
 and control of XML tags.</item>
                                 </itemize>
                             </item>
                             <item>
 Design the schema for an XML document
                             </item>
                             <item>
                                 <itemize>
                                     <item>Generate a document that includes (by ref or by value) a schema</item>
                                     <item>Develop scheme to permit dynamic cross-referencing 
 and indexing of XML objects.</item>
                                     <item>Disassemble document to materialize different query results
  into different tree structure</item>
                                     <item>Transmit sufficient metadata to construct alternate, semantically-valid
  views (e.g., XSL)</item>
                                    
                                 </itemize>
                             </item>
 
                         </itemize>
                     </text_body>
                 </p>
 
             </p>
         </p>
         <p id="4.4">
             <title>REGISTRY SERVICES</title>
             <text_body>The Registry shall provide standard APIs as specified in Appendix B.</text_body>
         </p>
         <p id="4.5">
             <title>DATA ACCESS SERVICES INTERNAL INTERFACE REQUIREMENTS</title>
             <text_body>The XS function shall provide standard APIs as specified in Appendix C.</text_body>
         </p>
         <p id="4.6">
             <p id="4.6.1">
                 <text_body>The XS shall internally interface (transparent to the operator) with the 
 existing data elements 
 of the DBIF, DAC, and COTS RDBMS products.</text_body>
             </p>
         </p>
         <p id="4.7">
             <title>REGISTRY SERVICES ENVIRONMENT REQUIREMENTS</title>
             <p id="4.7.1">
                 <text_body>The Registry software shall be portable and required to 
 execute on COE-compliant platforms.</text_body>
             </p>
         </p>
         <p id="4.8">
             <title>PERSONNEL-RELATED REQUIREMENTS</title>
             <text_body>Personnel requirements shall be determined by the developers of 
 the system in which the XS module is embedded</text_body>
         </p>
         <p id="4.9">
             <title>TRAINING-RELATED REQUIREMENTS</title>
             <text_body>Training requirements shall be determined by the developers of the 
 system in which the XS module is embedded.</text_body>
         </p>
         <p id="4.10">
             <title>LOGISTICS-RELATED REQUIREMENTS</title>
             <text_body>The XS developer is responsible for software maintenance, software 
 support, and software updates. The DISA Configuration Manager (CM) is responsible 
 for distribution of the XS 
 product to system developers.</text_body>
         </p>
         <p id="4.11">
             <title>OTHER REQUIREMENTS</title>
            
         </p>
         <p id="4.12">
             <title>PACKAGING REQUIREMENTS</title>
             <text_body>The XS software shall be delivered in accordance with DII COE guidelines.</text_body>
         </p>
         <p id="4.13">
         </p>
 
     </p>
     
 </req_document>