<req_document>
 
     <version>1.0</version>
     <p id= "1">
         <title>Introduction</title>
         <p id="1.1">
             <title>General overview of the VMUS (Voucher Maintenance Unit System) </title>
             <text_body>
                 <itemize>
                     <item>
 System Development: 
 The system will be developed on Oracle 9i platform Front end will be VB 
 (visual basic) Reports will be crystal reports 9 
                     </item>
                     <item>
 System design: 
 The system will be user friendly with maximum master table structure with 
 all transaction screens to have drop down selection menus to minimize data entry errors. 
 The main data entry screen on claims entry to have drop drown menu from patient’s profile 
 selection to medicine cost to have drop down. Minimize the use of keyboard for any number 
 entry to have a faster transaction data entry. The system will be easily trainable for the user 
 with minimum computer skill with simple user step by step manual. 
                     </item>
                     <item>
 Storage efficiency: 
 The structural design of the database will have sequential links with surrogate 
 keys. The database storage will be highly efficient to manage and avoid empty unused spaced 
 blocked, properly defragmenter on a periodic basis. This efficiency will have a maximum 
 provision to expand this program beyond the pilot period, 
 if the program requirements remain same. 
                     </item>
                     <item>
 Security: 
 High intrusion controls will be in place in the system and the database. 
 Access level controls, various organizational level user setting 
 by including granular model setting. 
                     </item>
                     <item>
 External Hardware interface: 
                         <itemize>
                             <item>
 Barcode:  
  the system will interface with the barcode reader to interface all transaction 
 details for example voucher number verifications, claim form entry and 
 selection of voucher usage by the clients.
                             </item>
                             <item>
 Biometrics:  the system will interface with the thumbprint reader for verifying claims form 
 used by the clients. 
                             </item>
                         </itemize>
                     </item>
                 </itemize>
             </text_body>
 
         </p>
 
     </p>
     <p id="2">
         <title>Overall Description</title>
         <p id="2.1">
             <title>System Perspective </title>
 
             <p id="2.1.2">
                 <title>2.1.2 Voucher Management System Modules </title>
                 <p id="1.">
                     <title> Voucher Creation / Preparation</title>
                     <text_body>Voucher creation:  the voucher numbers are system generated 
 and created with unique identification numbers with security protocols inbuilt. 
 The created unique numbers are then printed out in the form of barcodes, which will 
 complement (or stuck on the voucher) the voucher. Then at every level on the voucher 
 cycle this number is captured, on distribution, retail sales, point of treatment, enclosed 
 along with claim forms, at the claims processing and finally for the payment. 
 Such tracking records will be utilized for reports as well. Each voucher should have the 
 following properties, which will have subelements to get the batch numbers, voucher 
 numbers, and the project codes. Project code  Group batch code  Batch number  
 Voucher number  Security code.  
 
                     </text_body>
                     <p id="Design Constraints">
                         <text_body>This system has high security feature as far as the user access to the 
 system, including all the modules, 
 submodules and even at the screen level. 
                             <itemize>
                                 <item>The voucher will be created ONLY by the authorized person.</item>
                                 <item>The will be a provision to create a minimum quantity of vouchers at one time 
 (such minimum numbers will 
 be decided by the management team). </item>
                                 <item>Once created vouchers will not be edited or deleted but there will be a provision 
 to withhold any voucher number if the admin 
 team decides to do for any reason. </item>
                                 <item>There will be a provision to amend the validity date of the voucher. </item>
                             </itemize>
                         </text_body>
                     </p>
                 </p>
                 <p id="2.">
                     <title> Marketing / Sales </title>
                     <text_body>The marketing and sales is the next step and the next module in the system. 
 This module will take care of following sub modules. </text_body>
                     <p id="i">
                         <title>Distributor Master Information </title>
                         <text_body>The system will capture the master details of every distributor so that 
 the users can get the details of any distributor and sales details at any time. Each 
 distributor will have unique code and detailed descriptions such as name, address, 
 locations and type of business etc. such valid information will help us track 
 information related to sales and distributions. 
 Following fields will be captured at this master. 
    
                         </text_body>
                         <text_body>All fields with * are mandatory!</text_body>
                         <p id="Design Constraints">
                             <text_body>The address field will capture the geographical location of the distributor, 
 such as District, SubDistrict, County, SubCounty or Village / Town, road or street. All 
 the level of details will have a master table in order to update as per the program 
 requirements.  
 The system will check the duplicated ID for the distributors. The system can allow 
 the duplicate names of the Distributor. On capture of any duplicate name the system 
 will give a warning message to have the duplicate name or to change the name. 
 For better reporting purposes it is better to have a differentiating indicator on the name.  
 System will have a provision to print the distributor master details.  
 The distributor screen will have a provision to view the Sales History of a 
 particular distributor with following summary details.  
 Distributor Name as Report Header and following as the report footer 
 
                             </text_body>
                             <text_body>There will be a provision to select a particular distributor to view the details 
 (e.g. sales) by double clicking on the grid.  
 Print option of above report is based on User Login Permission only.  
 There will be an option for doing the following at every screen.
 
                             </text_body>
                             <text_body>There will also be a provision for the other users to view the details of a
  distributor with purchase and sales details.</text_body>
                         </p>
                     </p>
                     <p id="ii">
                         <text_body>The system will capture the details of MSIU Salesman; this would help 
 the MSIU management team to understand the performance of each Team or salesman. 
 During every distribution transaction the user should select the name of the sales man 
 listed from Team Master. 
 The Salesman master should capture following information’s. 
 
                         </text_body>
                         <text_body>The sales team master is for the future development of this program, 
 if this program is extended to a countrywide network, 
 this master will help understand and tack sales information. </text_body>
                         <p id="Design Constraints">
                             <text_body>The system will check the duplicated ID for the salesman and team. 
 The system can allow the duplicate names of the salesman. On capture of any duplicate 
 name the system will give a warning message to have the duplicate name or to change 
 the name. For better reporting purposes 
 it is better to have a differentiating indicator on the name</text_body>
                         </p>
                     </p>
                     <p id="iii">
                         <title>Distribution Transactions (Sales from MSIU to Distributor) </title>
                         <text_body>The system will capture the details of voucher sales between MISU 
 sales team and Distributors. During the distribution the system will capture the 
 following details, to make Distribution process easily. With the below details the 
 user can get the details of Distributor wise and Salesman wise 
 and Batch No wise sales details as reports. 
 
                         </text_body>
                         <p id="Design Constraints">
 
                             <text_body>The system will generate an autogenerated number as Distribution 
 Invoice No.  
 Suppose the distributor or salesman name is not available in the system, then the 
 system has a provision to navigate quickly to its master screen and enter the new 
 Distributor and Salesman details, 
 without closing the present screen.  
 While entering the No of vouchers required, the system should automatically 
 pick the Batch No’s with voucher No’s from the available voucher stock and list the 
 details of each voucher with below information’s as a grid format. 
    
                             </text_body>
                             <text_body>The date of distribution will be current (system) date, but the date of sale 
 can be the past dates. 
 There will be a future date sale validation check available. </text_body>
                         </p>
                     </p>
                 </p>
             </p>
             <p id="3.">
                 <title>Claim Entry/Processing</title>
                 <text_body>The program will take maximum care in this form and table, as it 
 become a vital transaction to be captured. In this module you will see that every 
 capture of data will be 
 validated and checked on saving into the database. For e.g. the capture of voucher 
 number, clinical information, diagnosis details, drug and investigation details and 
 the costs are going to provide the program a vital report information. The system 
 development team will focus its attention in making this module/table function 
 efficiently.  For the easy understanding and designing of the system, this module is 
 subdivided into following submodules. The division of submodule is purely based 
 on the sublevel categories of the data information. 
 
                 </text_body>
                 <p id="i">
                     <title>Voucher Service Provider (VSP) Master Information </title>
                     <p id="Design Constraints">
                         <text_body>Other than Contact No and EMail Id all other information are mandatory 
 during the creation of a new Service Provider.  
 The VSP code is a digit code with suffix SP, would be automatically generated by the 
 system.  
 The system should generate message with two option “Continue  Yes/No” while the 
 user trying to create a new VSP with an existing name, If the user press Yes the 
 system will allow the user to enter the same, if not the system wont allow the new 
 entry to save.  
 The system will list District, SubDistrict, County, SubCounty, Village / Town 
 from the master during VSP creation, if any of them are not available in the system, 
 then the system will have the provision to navigate quickly to its master screen and 
 do enter master details and back to VSP screen.   
 The values of Health Sub  District, Locality, Level Of Facility, Type of facility, 
 Registration Body would be list from their own master and should select the details 
 based on the VSP. If any of the information is not available in existing master of 
 above, then the system will have the provision to navigate quickly to its form to 
 enter the master details and back to VSP Screen. The system will populate Active VSP 
 only on other screen during data entry process, 
 but the system will also populate all VSP for report purpose.  
 Activation and Inactivation of VSP is purely based on the MSIU Management decision. 
 But if the system is found more than two fraud entries during the claim process of 
 particular VSP, then the system would automatically change the status of that particular 
 VSP as Inactivate. Activation of that particular VSP is again purely based on MSIU 
 Management decision.  
 The VSP Master Information screen should have a provision to enter the payment terms 
 agreed between MSIU and VSP. The system will capture following master details to fill 
 the payment terms. 
            
                         </text_body>
      
                         <text_body>The above mentioned payment terms will help the MSIU to make the 
 payment detail easy and also help the VSP to get their payment in timeThe system will 
 control the payment process and terms.  The allowed users only can able to Add, Modify 
 or delete the VSP master information including payment terms.  
 The VSP screen will have the provision to view the Claim Status of selected VSP. The 
 system will facilitate to show the user following details if necessary.  
 VSP Name (as the report header and below as the details part of report) 
   
                         </text_body>
                         <text_body>Cumulative Total Amount will show in Report footer for the previous payment done. </text_body>
                     </p>
                 </p>
                 <p id="ii">
                     <title>VSP Staff Master Information </title>
                     <text_body>The system will have the facility to capture the details of VSP staff 
 details and the necessary master information 
 while entering the claim into the system.
 
                     </text_body>
                     <p id="Design Contraints">
                         <text_body>The system will generate message while creating a new staff with 
 existing name, but the system will allow 
 the user to save that new staff if its required. 
 All above information’s other than Qualification are mandatory during 
 the creation of new staff under any VSP.  
 The system will automatically create Staff Code with Suffix as VSP Code 
 + SC + 3 digit. For example HP0001SC0001  
 Staff type (should be select from list of staff type listing from Staff Type Master)  
 If any of the staff type is not available in the system, then the system should 
 have the provision to navigate quickly to staff type master 
 to enter the new staff type and then back to Staff Master screen. </text_body>
                     </p>
                 </p>
                 <p id="iii">
                     <title>Claim (Treatment Form) Submission </title>
                     <text_body>Depends on the payment terms (Bimonthly / Monthly) mentioned in 
 the VSP master the VSP should submit the Claim (Treatment form) to the MISU Field 
 office. While submitting the Claim (Treatment Form) to MSIU, the system will have 
 the provision to capture the following details. These information is vital and 
 shall be used for compared with the processed claims. 
 
                     </text_body>
                     <p id="Design Constraints">
                         <text_body>
                             <itemize>
                                 <item>During submission entry all above information’s are mandatory</item>
                                 <item>Date of submission should be current date </item>
                                 <item>The system lists the VSP Name from VSP Master. </item>
                                 <item>Mentioned Forms and Available Forms only accept numeric values. </item>
                                 <item>Available forms may be less than or greater than or equal to Mentioned Forms. </item>
                                 <item>In the transaction part no of forms should match with No of Available Forms </item>
                             </itemize>
                         </text_body>
                         <text_body>The system should print a receipt document based on the information 
 entered during claim submission. 
 The document should have the following information. 
 
                         </text_body>
                     </p>
                 </p>
                 <p id="iv">
                     <text_body>The claim entry is purely based on the Treatment (claims) Form submitted 
 by the VSP. Before the claim entry the user should check the form manually to understand 
 whether any mandatory information is missed in the Claim or not. If yes, then the user 
 should mark that Claim (Treatment Form) status as Rejected and send back to VSP.  
 During the claim entry the system should capture the following information. 
 
                     </text_body>
                     <text_body>The above details are the master informationd and below listed information
 are the transaction details of a Claim.</text_body>
 
 
                     <p id="For Second Follow UP">
 
                         <text_body>The system will have the provision to enter any number of Syndrome, 
 Clinical Examinations, Diagnosis, Lab Test, Drugs and Other Measures in 
 any treatment level based on MSIU treatment master. </text_body>
                     </p>
                     <p id="Design Constraints">
                         <text_body>All above master level information are mandatory other than 
 Contact No during the entry of claim into the system. The following part will 
 explain how the systems 
 will validate every information during claim entry. 
                             <itemize>
                <item>The system will automatically generate the Claim number with Hospital 
 Code as Suffix + 8 digit </item>
                                 <item> 
 if any details are not exist in Master record, then the system should have the provision 
 to navigate quickly to its master screen to enter the new details 
 and back to the Claim Entry Screen </item>
                                                                
                                 <item>
 Patient Status: 
 suppose the status is Referral then the system will have the provision to capture 
 Referred To and Reason for Referral, the reason for Referral 
 should be populated from Referral master. 
                                 </item>
                                 <item>
 Claim Status: 
 Status of the claim is depends information available in the 
 Claim, if any false data or any mandatory information is available in 
 Claim, then the claims status will change. if the value of status is not 
 “Accepted” then the claim will be stored in quarantine area and can able 
 to precede it further from its status. The system should have a provision 
 to capture the reason suppose if the claim status is “Rejection or Quarantine” 
 
                                 </item>
                                 <item>
 Claim Amount  
 The calculation of claim amount is explained below. 
                                 </item>
                             </itemize>
                         </text_body>
                         <text_body>If it is a First visit Claim
                             <itemize>
                                 <item>Claim Amount will capture First Visit Consultation Fee 
 (from VSP Payment terms) + Lab test Amount (from VSP Payment terms) 
 + (Qty of drugs * Retails Price (from Drugs Master).</item>
                             </itemize>
                         </text_body>
                         <text_body>If Claim is for first follow up 
                             <itemize>
                                 <item>Claim Amount will capture First Follow up Fee (from VSP Payment terms) + 
 (Qty of drugs * Retails Price (from Drugs Master)</item>
                             </itemize>
                         </text_body>
                         <text_body>If Claim is for second follow up 
                             <itemize>
                                 <item>Claim Amount will capture Second Follow up Fee (from VSP Payment terms) + 
 (Qty of drugs * Retails Price (from Drugs Master)</item>
                             </itemize>
                         </text_body>
                         <text_body>The system captures the thump impression available in each claim 
 form, and needs to compare it with the same voucher numbers previous visits 
 if available. If the thump impression are mismatching for the same patient 
 (Client / Partner) on same voucher the system would automatically make a count on it.  
  If the claim from same VSP having more than two times of Thump Impression 
 mismatching, then the system should automatically produce a warning message 
 and the same time the system should InActivate the VSP. 
 The authorized user can alter / amend the Claim if required. 
                         </text_body>
                     </p>
                     
                     <p id="Assumptions">
                         <text_body>
                             <itemize>
                          
                                 <item>The user should enter the information exactly into the 
 system from the manual claim form </item>
                              
                                 <item>System only accept claims only if the mandatory information is complete </item>
                                 <item>System should calculate Claim Amount only based on treatment matrix </item>
                             </itemize>
                         </text_body>
                     </p>
                 </p>
             </p>
             <p id="4.">
                 <title>Voucher Sales Return </title>
                 <text_body>
 Voucher Sales return is feature used when a distributor is planning to 
 return the vouchers back to the MSIU sales team. The system will 
 capture the following information during the sales return transaction. 
 
                 </text_body>
 
                 <p id="Design Constraints">
 
                     <text_body>While entering return vouchers details the system will check weather 
 the returned voucher was sold to this particular Distributor or not. 
 If not the system won’t accept those vouchers as return. </text_body>
                 </p>
             </p>
             <p id="5.">
                 <text_body>MSIU team collects the client feedback from the clients who 
 got treatment through the voucher system. 
 The Client Feedback form should capture the following details 
 
                 </text_body>
                 <p id="Design Constraints">
                 </p>
                 <p id="Assumptions">
                     <text_body>
                         <itemize>
                             <item>The user should enter correct Voucher No </item>
                             <item>The user will not alter any information about treatment, 
 which is populating from the system </item>
                         </itemize>
                     </text_body>
                 </p>
             </p>
             <p id="6.">
                 <title>Reports (Standard and Customized) </title>
                 <text_body>The system has the provision to provide various analytical, medical, 
 financial and statistical 
 reports, such reports can be designed later.</text_body>
             </p>
             <p id="7.">
                 <title>Security and User Privileges </title>
                 <text_body>The security setting of the entire system is based on User Group. 
 The roles available in the system are allocated to user group. 
 The user group creation would capture the following Information
                 </text_body>
 
                 <p id="Design Constraints">
                     <text_body>Allow above information are mandatory while creating a new User Group. 
                         <itemize>
                             <item>The system admin only can able to create User Groups 
                             </item>
                             <item>The system should have the provision to create any 
 number of individual user under any user group. 
                             </item>
                         </itemize>
                     </text_body>
                     <text_body>All the above are mandatory entry
                         <itemize>
                             <item>The system should save the user information only if the 
 Password and Verify password values are equal </item>
                             <item>The system should not allow the user to create a User 
 Group and Individual User with existing names</item>
                         </itemize>
                     </text_body>
                 </p>
             </p>
         </p>
     </p>
 
 </req_document>