<req_document>
 
     <p id="2">
         <title>GENERAL DESCRIPTION</title>
         <p id="2.1">
             <title>Product Perspective</title>
             <p id="2.1.1">
                 <title>User Interfaces</title>
                 <text_body>The product runs as a standalone application.
 Its user interface uses menus, graphics and sounds.</text_body>
             </p>
             <p id="2.1.2">
                 <title>Hardware Interfaces</title>
                 <text_body>The product requires the use of a keyboard and a mouse to interface with the
 user. It requires a graphical display of at least 800*600 resolution.</text_body>
             </p>
             <p id="2.1.3">
                 <title>Software Interfaces</title>
                 <text_body>The product uses the Qt graphical library. It must run with all the operating
 systems that Qt supports.</text_body>
             </p>
 
         </p>
         <p id="2.2">
             <title>Product Functions</title>
             <p id="2.2.1">
                 <title>Undo et Redo Actions.</title>
                 <text_body>The user must undo and redo its last thousand actions.</text_body>
             </p>
             <p id="2.2.2">
                 <title>Time passed to play.</title>
                 <text_body>The product must count and display the time that the user uses to play.</text_body>
             </p>
             <p id="2.2.3">
                 <title>Count of action number.</title>
                 <text_body>The product must count and display the number of the user' asction.</text_body>
             </p>
             <p id="2.2.4">
                 <title>Score.</title>
                 <text_body>The product must record the score (time and number of counts) of a play
 associated with the name of a user.</text_body>
             </p>
             <p id="2.2.5">
                 <title>Score window.</title>
                 <text_body>The product must display a window with all the player' scores.</text_body>
             </p>
         </p>
 
     </p>
     <p id="3">
         <title>SPECIFIC REQUIREMENTS</title>
         <p id="3.1">
             <title>External Interfaces</title>
             <text_body>The product generally requires a mouse and a keyboard for input. Other pointing
 and input devices are allowable, provided they provide similar functions to a
 mouse and keyboard, namely the ability to move a cursor onscreen to select
 buttons and the ability to type names.
 The product uses menus, graphics and sounds. The hardware and operating
 system must provide an 800x600 screen resolution. Sound is not required to play
 the game.</text_body>
             <p id="3.1.1">
                 <title>User Interfaces</title>
                 <p id="3.1.1.1">
                     <title>Introduction</title>
                     <text_body>The users consist of anyone who wants to play a simple game who knows how to
 operate a computer, with a beginning level player starting at age 8, up through an
 advanced level player who could be an adult.</text_body>
                 </p>
                 <p id="3.1.1.2">
                     <title>Main window</title>
                     <text_body>The main window shall provide the following parts :
                         <itemize>
                             <item>A board</item>
                             <item>a menu bar</item>
                         </itemize>
                     </text_body>
                 </p>
             </p>
 
         </p>
 
 
         <p id="3.3">
             <title>3.3Performance Requirements</title>
             <text_body>There can be only one user per machine.</text_body>
         </p>
         <p id="3.4">
             <title>Software System Attributes</title>
             <text_body>The software must be portable to the Windows OS.</text_body>
         </p>
     </p>
     
 </req_document>